<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IWCP: University of Michigan</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on IWCP: University of Michigan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Test</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-09-24-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-09-24-test/</guid>
      <description>Test</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anil Menon</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-09-10-menon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-09-10-menon/</guid>
      <description>Refugees and the Radical Right: Evidence from Post-WWII Forced Migrations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samuel Baltz</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-08-13-baltz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-08-13-baltz/</guid>
      <description>A direct approach to understanding how electoral systems affect election results</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justine Davis</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-08-06-davis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-08-06-davis/</guid>
      <description>Democratization by NGOs in Africa: Ethnic Inequities in Post-Conflict Civil Society</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuannuan Xiang</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-07-17-xiang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-07-17-xiang/</guid>
      <description>Varieties of Maternalist States: Saving Mothers and Infants in the United States and Japan in the Early Twentieth Century</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pauline Jones</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-06-18-jones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-06-18-jones/</guid>
      <description>TBD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hojung Joo</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-06-11-joo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-06-11-joo/</guid>
      <description>Prewar Mobilization and Violence Against Civilians: Evidence from the Korean War</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joe Klaver</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-04-09-klaver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-04-09-klaver/</guid>
      <description>Institutions and the Generation and Adjudication of Post-Election Disputes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas O&#39;Mealia</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-04-02-omealia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-04-02-omealia/</guid>
      <description>Mines and the Road to Violence: Why armed group revenue generating schemes displace fighting in resource abundant conflicts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebecca Savelsberg and Mark Tessler</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-03-26-savelsberg-and-tessler/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-03-26-savelsberg-and-tessler/</guid>
      <description>*Sex-Linked Differences in Arab Attitudes toward the Islamic State: Evidence from an Arab Barometer Survey and Experiment</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wooseok Kim</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-03-19-kim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-03-19-kim/</guid>
      <description>Party System Institutionalization: Concept and Measurement using a Bayesian Latent Variable Model</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guoer Liu</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-03-12-liu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-03-12-liu/</guid>
      <description>The Clash of Traditional Values: Attitudes toward a Male-line Monarchy under a Succession Crisis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitchell Bosley and Htet Thiha Zaw</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-03-05-bosley-and-zaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-03-05-bosley-and-zaw/</guid>
      <description>Does Franchise Expansion Affect Legislative Activity?: Evidence from British India Legislative Debates, 1901-1940</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charlotte Cavaille</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-02-26-cavaille/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-02-26-cavaille/</guid>
      <description>What Should We Do About Debt? Understanding How People Reason About Fiscal Stress and Debt Sustainability
There has been tons of work in CPE and IPE on individual preferences about redistribution, trade or immigration policy. A few papers are starting to pop-up on attitudes toward fiscal policy but overall, the research is pretty limited. We see this project as providing a descriptive first step covering fundamental questions such as: are debt and deficits on people’s minds?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faculty Panel: U.S. as a Comparative Case (recording available)</title>
      <link>/all-events/2021-02-19-u.s.-comparative-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2021-02-19-u.s.-comparative-case/</guid>
      <description>Panelists: Jenna Bednar, Rob Mickey, Dan Slater and Charlotte Cavaille
 Recording available here.  After the events of January 6 and the past four years, there has been an increased interest in looking at the United States as another case of rising populist authoritarianism and potential democratic backsliding. This follows a trend of comparativists urging others not to see the U.S. as an &amp;quot;exceptional&amp;quot; case, and to learn lessons from other country cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reuben Hurst</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-12-04-hurst/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-12-04-hurst/</guid>
      <description>Workplace populism? Demographic Change and White Worker Reactions to Pro Diversity Language</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sarah Denise Rozenblum</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-11-13-rozenblum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-11-13-rozenblum/</guid>
      <description>Quo Vadis Public health: the rise and crisis of a professional project in France and in the United States</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Thompson-Brusstar</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-11-06-thompson-brusstar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-11-06-thompson-brusstar/</guid>
      <description>Supervision Science: Institutional Design in Chinese Anticorruption</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simeon Newman</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-10-30-newman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-10-30-newman/</guid>
      <description>Mass Clientelism: A Mode of Political Intermediation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Lerner</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-10-23-lerner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-10-23-lerner/</guid>
      <description>Transnational advocacy catalyzes environmental policy leadership</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anil Menon</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-10-16-menon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-10-16-menon/</guid>
      <description>Refugees and the Radical Right: Evidence from Post-WWII Forced Migrations
Do refugees reshape long-term political behavior in receiving areas? To investigate this question, I examine the expulsion of ethnic Germans from Eastern Europe into West Germany at the end of WWII. Expellees were strangers to the cultural practices in their new surroundings. Tensions with natives forced expellees to rely on each other and helped foster a strong group identity. I argue that this shared identity, coupled with political circumstances specific to Germany, engendered support for the radical right among expellees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sasha de Vogel</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-10-09-devogel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-10-09-devogel/</guid>
      <description>The Dynamics of Everyday Protest in High-Capacity Autocracies
How do high-capacity authoritarian governments respond to protests that do not threaten the regime? Everyday protests policy-specific grievances constitute a large yet overlooked share of protests in authoritarian states, and exhibit fundamentally different dynamics from commonly studied opposition protests. I argue that everyday protest dynamics are determined by the institutional factors that generate different types of underlying policy grievances. Grievances related to new policies, about which the government has restricted to policy exclusion protest campaigns, whereas grievances related tostatic policies, about which the government has lower information, produce policy erosion campaigns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Htet Thiha Zaw</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-10-02-zaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-10-02-zaw/</guid>
      <description>Repression and (Re)Education: A Theory of Institutional Change in Colonial Education
Why did colonial states expand their involvement in educating their indigenous populations? Observed across colonial Southeast Asia, this phenomenon&#39;s characteristic feature is not explained by existing research: a policy change from the early support for indigenous providers to their later replacement by secular and missionary schools. To illustrate this, I conceptualize colonial education as a commitment problem, where the government, despite economic benefits from education, faces the risk of anti-colonial resistance from the educated population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tom O&#39;Mealia</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-09-25-omealia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-09-25-omealia/</guid>
      <description>Protection and the Origins of Institutional Trust: Evidence from Protection Rackets in Eastern DRCongo
As armed actors attempt to establish local monopolies on violence, civilians face a dangerous choice: do they trust the armed group to provide security, exchanging regular tribute for protection from violence, despite their limited leverage to stop the security provider from abusing their coercive power? Or do they reject the armed actors by fleeing, passively resisting, or attempting to provide security themselves?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iza Ding (University of Pittsburgh)</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-05-01-ding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-05-01-ding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edgar Franco Vivanco</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-03-20-franco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-03-20-franco/</guid>
      <description>A Taxonomy of Criminal Governance: Evidence from Rio de Janeiro
Why did colonial powers establish courts to address Indigenous grievances? Under which conditions did these rulers decide to rule in favor of Indigenous claimants, even at the expense of their own state agents? This paper addresses these questions by studying the legal battles between Indigenous communities, Spanish settlers, and local bureaucrats in the General Indian Court of colonial Mexico (GIC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike Thompson-Brusstar</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-03-13-thompson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-03-13-thompson/</guid>
      <description>Multiple Supervision in Reform China
I provide a research memo that is part of the design for a proposed dissertation chapter. Because it’s a “later” chapter, it takes a lot of things as given. I try to cover that ground quickly on the front end of the memo. I welcome comments about any aspect of the memo, but I am particularly perplexed by how to resolve some of the problems with the theory-to-empirical strategy match-up that I discuss in the research design section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Htet Thiha Zaw</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-02-28-zaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-02-28-zaw/</guid>
      <description>How to Repel a Rebel: State Presence in Colonial Burma
My dissertation project seeks to understand the strategy behind the colonial states in pursuing the two types of state-building process: (1) investments in physical coercion, and (2) investments in education. The project will look at what functions these two processes can serve to the colonial states, and consequently, what the colonial states pursued, when there is a risk of economic instability and violent conflict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johannes Urpelainen (Johns Hopkins University)</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-02-21-urpelainen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-02-21-urpelainen/</guid>
      <description>How Effective Are Political Solutions to Ethnic Bias? Caste and Clean Drinking Water in Rural India
Social scientists have documented prevalent ingroup bias in human societies, but the empirical evidence on effective strategies to reduce such unequal treatment to marginalized groups remains thin. We focus on caste-based bias in India’s largest state, Uttar Pradesh, with a population of 200 million and one-fifth of them from the lower castes (Dalits, or scheduled castes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Lerner</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-02-14-lerner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-02-14-lerner/</guid>
      <description>Do interaction and advocacy catalyze environmental policy leadership?
International efforts to address environmental challenges increasingly rely on the information, capacity, and will of policymakers to act as policy leaders at the national level. What countries have taken the lead in the development of environmental policy? Do international interaction and transnational advocacy catalyze environmental policy leadership? Combining a novel network-based measurement approach and a new database of environmental policy innovation adoptions, I will dynamically measure environmental policy leadership at the global level and estimate its relationship with interaction and advocacy using causally-identified spatial and network regression models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia Maynard</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-02-07-maynard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-02-07-maynard/</guid>
      <description>Usurping the Leader: A Comparative Analysis of Party Leadership Changes
Co-authored with Christine Sylvester (University of Binghamton)
Party leaders are seen as the face and central control of a political party’s agenda (also possibly the legislature). This asks the question, with all this power why would a leader ever relinquish their position? Little work has looked comparatively at why leaders step down from office due to data limitations. We contribute to the literature on party politics and leader tenure by providing a new dataset of leadership changes in advanced industrial democracies from 1960-2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anil Menon</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-01-31-menon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-01-31-menon/</guid>
      <description>Warring Memories: The Political Behavior Legacies of World War II in Germany
Does conflict-induced resettlement produce durable political behavior legacies? I investigate this question by focusing on the expulsion of ethnic Germans from Eastern Europe into West Germany at the end of World War II. These expellees wanted to regain their lost lands and for broader society to acknowledge their suffering. In time, such demands for recognition and restitution received little support outside far-right parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hojung Joo</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-01-24-joo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-01-24-joo/</guid>
      <description>Colonial grievances and uprisings in Korea
Does history matter when it comes to explaining violence against civilians during wars? How does a region’s history of communal conflict or resistance against authority influence the intentional killing of civilians by armed groups? In this paper, I argue that a region that have more records of economic tension among villagers also experience more violence against civilians during future armed conflicts. I further argue that a region’s record of resistance against authority, conditional on the relationship between past and current authorities, can lead to more civilian killings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tom O&#39;Mealia</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-01-17-omealia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-01-17-omealia/</guid>
      <description>Local Trust in UN Peacekeeping Operations: Survey Evidence from DRCongo
Peacekeeping operations rely on the support of the local population both to gather information and to solidify peace. To gain such support, missions must cultivate trust with the residents in the areas in which they operate. We develop a theory of a transactional model of trust with international peacekeeping missions: those who interact with and benefit from UN peacekeeping missions are more likely to trust it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sasha de Vogel</title>
      <link>/all-events/2020-01-10-devogel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2020-01-10-devogel/</guid>
      <description>Information, Concessions and Reneging in Authoritarian Regimes
How does information affect how autocratic governments make concessions to subnational protest campaigns? I argue the strategic purpose of concessions varies depending on the level of information about the grievance available to the government. In cases where the government has little prior awareness of the motivating grievance, protests convey valuable new information, and concessions are used as a long-term adaptation strategy, to eliminate grievances and prevent citizens from becoming regime opponents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deanna Kolberg</title>
      <link>/all-events/2019-11-22-kolberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2019-11-22-kolberg/</guid>
      <description>Informal Communities and Data Reporting Bias
In addition to buying and selling votes, brokers are often simultaneously in positions of community leadership working on advocacy and governance. Brokerage and community work can in some cases be complementary- the broker’s community work helps build a network which they can leverage to buy votes- but can also be rivalrous { a broker’s electoral work can make their governance efforts more difficult. Does changes in the political environment effect effort and outcomes in grassroots governance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sarah Khan (Yale University)</title>
      <link>/all-events/2019-11-08-khan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2019-11-08-khan/</guid>
      <description>Canvassing the Gatekeepers: A Field Experiment to Increase Women’s Electoral Turnout in Pakistan
Ali Cheema, Sarah Khan, Asad Liaqat, and Shandana Khan Mohmand
Abstract
Pakistan has one of the largest gender gaps in turnout among electoral democracies around the world. A widely tested strategy to encourage turnout in a variety of contexts is door-to-door voter canvassing or mobilization. We use a field experiment conducted with 2500 households in the city of Lahore to study the effectiveness of this strategy in increasing women’s turnout in the 2018 Pakistan General Election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nahomi Ichino</title>
      <link>/all-events/2019-11-01-ichino/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2019-11-01-ichino/</guid>
      <description>Methods of Differences: Credible Research Design and Analysis with Qualitative Information
Co-Authored with Adam Glynn (Emory University)
Please join us for Nahomi’s presentation on November 1, 2019.
Download the paper here (U-M only)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Job Talk: Todd Lehmann</title>
      <link>/all-events/2019-10-11-lehmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2019-10-11-lehmann/</guid>
      <description>Projecting Credibility: Alliance Commitments, Security Partnerships, and International Crisis Responses
Todd Lehmann
Abstract
How does the ability to quickly project large-scale military force—such as with transport aircraft and naval aircraft carriers—affect states’ alliances and security partnerships? I argue that states with greater capacity to project force will deploy fewer troops to allies for deterrent purposes. Instead, more capable states can demonstrate their commitment to allies through public words and actions—such as statements by political leaders—supported by the ability to quickly respond to crises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Job Talk: Yilang Feng</title>
      <link>/all-events/2019-10-04-feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2019-10-04-feng/</guid>
      <description>Regulatory Arbitrage and Overseas Operation of Multinational Firms
Yilang Feng
Abstract
How does a firm’s global production affect its political strategy to shape its home country regulatory policies? This question lies at the intersection of globalization and corporate political actions, and it is becoming increasingly relevant today with nationalist discontent challenging the global order. To address this question, I develop a theory of regulatory arbitrage: in response to unfavorable regulatory outcomes at home, it is easier for firms with overseas operations to offshore more of their domestic operations abroad, resulting in an outflow of capital and jobs from the home country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronald Inglehart</title>
      <link>/all-events/2019-09-20-inglehart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2019-09-20-inglehart/</guid>
      <description>“From Authoritarian Personality to Authoritarian Reflex- Evolving Views of an Enduring Phenomenon”
Please join us for Ron’s talk on September 20th from 1:00-2:30 in the PreFunction Room.
Download the paper here (U-M only)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kirill Zhirkov</title>
      <link>/all-events/2019-09-13-zhirkov/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2019-09-13-zhirkov/</guid>
      <description>The Political Relevance of Implicit and Explicit Racialized Schemas about Immigrant Origins: Evidence from the United States and Britain
Kirill Zhirkov
Empirical research consistently demonstrates the importance of racial attitudes in structuring public opinion and political behavior. In this paper, I suggest that the degree to which natives think of immigrants in racial terms is strongly related to attitudes toward immigration. Using the schematic approach to social cognition, I argue that mental associations (schemas) linking immigration to race are formed on the level of origin groups, not individual immigrants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WCED Colloquium on Authoritarian Politics: Iza Ding and Jeffrey Javed</title>
      <link>/all-events/2019-09-12-ding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/all-events/2019-09-12-ding/</guid>
      <description>Red Memory: Nostalgia, Trauma, and Public Opinion in Contemporary China
Iza Ding (University of Pittsburg) and Jeffrey Javed (University of Michigan)
Abstract
How do citizens remember the political past and how do these memories shape their views of present-day politics? We examine the formation of political memory and its relationship with individual attitudes toward contemporary government policies in China, focusing on Chinese citizens’ memories of the Maoist era (1949-1976). On the basis of 77 intensive semi-structured interviews in four cities, we find that Maoist nostalgia—where it exists—is a reaction to the profound feeling of moral disenchantment many Chinese citizens feel over the complex societal challenges resulting from China’s extraordinary four-decade arc of economic reform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>The Interdisciplinary Workshop in Comparative Politics (IWCP) provides a platform for sharing and improving research that provides comparative perspectives on the causes and effects of political and economic processes. We have participants from Economics, the Ford School of Public Policy, the Law School, the Lieberthal-Rogel Center for Chinese Studies, Mathematics, Political Science, the Ross School of Business, Sociology, Statistics, and the Weiser Center for Emerging Democracies.
Workshops meet from 1--2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>Comparative Politics Reading Lists  Over the past decade, graduate students in the Political Science department have created a valuable common pool resource consisting of course syllabi, reading lists for preliminary exams, and reading notes and summaries. This resource provides a foundation for scholars interested in becoming familiar with the literature on comparative politics. This resource is accessible to University of Michigan-affiliated individuals at this link.
 Funding Opportunities List  Originally provided courtesy of Professor Mark Tessler, this is a document listing a variety of internal and external funding opportunities for comparative politics research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
