<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IWCP: University of Michigan</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on IWCP: University of Michigan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation: Sarah Khan (Yale University)</title>
      <link>/2019/11/08/presentation-sarah-khan-yale-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/08/presentation-sarah-khan-yale-university/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for a guest speaker, Sarah Khan, on November 8, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation: Nahomi Ichino</title>
      <link>/2019/11/01/presentation-nahomi-ichino/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/01/presentation-nahomi-ichino/</guid>
      <description>Methods of Differences: Credible Research Design and Analysis with Qualitative Information
Co-Authored with Adam Glynn (Emory University)
Please join us for Nahomi’s presentation on November 1, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Job Talk: Todd Lehmann</title>
      <link>/2019/10/11/practice-job-talk-todd-lehmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/11/practice-job-talk-todd-lehmann/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for Todd Lehmann’s practice job talk on October 11, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Job Talk: Yilang Feng</title>
      <link>/2019/10/04/practice-job-talk-yilang-feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/04/practice-job-talk-yilang-feng/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for Yilang Feng’s practice job talk on October 4, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation: Deanna Kolberg</title>
      <link>/2019/09/22/presentation-deanna-kolberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/22/presentation-deanna-kolberg/</guid>
      <description>Informal Communities and Data Reporting Bias
Please join us for Deanna’s talk on November 22, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation: Ronald Inglehart</title>
      <link>/2019/09/20/presentation-ronald-inglehart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/20/presentation-ronald-inglehart/</guid>
      <description>“From Authoritarian Personality to Authoritarian Reflex- Evolving Views of an Enduring Phenomenon”
Please join us for Ron’s talk on September 20th from 1:00-2:30 in the PreFunction Room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Job Talk: Kirill Zhirkov</title>
      <link>/2019/09/13/practice-job-talk-kirill-zhirkov/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/13/practice-job-talk-kirill-zhirkov/</guid>
      <description>The Political Relevance of Implicit and Explicit Racialized Schemas about Immigrant Origins: Evidence from the United States and Britain
In 5450 North Quad in the Communication and Media Conference Room
Empirical research consistently demonstrates the importance of racial attitudes in structuring public opinion and political behavior. In this paper, I suggest that the degree to which natives think of immigrants in racial terms is strongly related to attitudes toward immigration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WCED Colloquium on Authoritarian Politics: Iza Ding and Jeffrey Javed</title>
      <link>/2019/09/12/wced-colloquium-on-authoritarian-politics-iza-ding-and-jeffrey-javed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/12/wced-colloquium-on-authoritarian-politics-iza-ding-and-jeffrey-javed/</guid>
      <description>Red Memory: Nostalgia, Trauma, and Public Opinion in Contemporary China
Iza Ding (University of Pittsburg) and Jeffrey Javed (University of Michigan)
Abstract
How do citizens remember the political past and how do these memories shape their views of present-day politics? We examine the formation of political memory and its relationship with individual attitudes toward contemporary government policies in China, focusing on Chinese citizens’ memories of the Maoist era (1949-1976). On the basis of 77 intensive semi-structured interviews in four cities, we find that Maoist nostalgia—where it exists—is a reaction to the profound feeling of moral disenchantment many Chinese citizens feel over the complex societal challenges resulting from China’s extraordinary four-decade arc of economic reform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>The Interdisciplinary Workshop in Comparative Politics (IWCP) provides a platform for sharing and improving research that provides comparative perspectives on the causes and effects of political and economic processes. We have participants from Economics, the Ford School of Public Policy, the Law School, the Lieberthal-Rogel Center for Chinese Studies, Mathematics, Political Science, the Ross School of Business, Sociology, Statistics, and the Weiser Center for Emerging Democracies.
Workshops meet from 1–2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>Comparative Politics Reading Lists  Over the past decade, graduate students in the Political Science department have created a valuable common pool resource consisting of course syllabi, reading lists for preliminary exams, and reading notes and summaries. This resource provides a foundation for scholars interested in becoming familiar with the literature on comparative politics. This resource is accessible to University of Michigan-affiliated individuals at this link.
 Funding Opportunities List  Originally provided courtesy of Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/</guid>
      <description>Hello
{{ partial “header.html” . }}
{{ if .Content }} {{ if .Title }} {{ .Title }}  {{ end }}  {{ .Content }} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;  {{ end }} {{ $pages := .Pages }} {{ if .IsHome }} {{ $pages = .Site.RegularPages }} {{ end }} {{ range (where $pages &amp;quot;Section&amp;quot; &amp;quot;!=&amp;quot; &amp;quot;&amp;quot;).GroupByDate &amp;quot;2006&amp;quot; }} &amp;lt;h2 class=&amp;quot;article-title&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{ .Key }}&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt; {{ range .Pages }} &amp;lt;article class=&amp;quot;article-item&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;{{ .RelPermalink }}&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;article-item-link&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{ .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>